Eric Gustafson

Sr Staff Systems Engineer

Contact

Address

HIGHLANDS RANCH, CO, 80129

Phone

(720) 346-5341

E-mail

weuxfya@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-gustafson-4006b4/

WWW

https://github.com/ericgustafson1

Skills

JavaScipt
HTML/CSS Bootstrap
MySQL / Sequelize
Infrastructure
PowerShell
Node.js / Express
GitHub / BitBucket
REST APIs / Web Services
JSON
MongoDB / Mongoose

Systems Engineer with 10+ years of experience in Infrastructure-as-a-Service roles. Experience with compute, storage, virtualization. Scripting and development skillsets. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving operational improvements. Prioritize work in the context of meeting business needs while moving toward group goals.

Work History

2012-04 -Current

Sr Staff Systems Engineer

VISA, Highlands Ranch, Colorado

- Collaborated with private cloud team providing PowerShell scripts for automating hypervisor build configuration and validation.
- Partnered with Visa Operations team and Microsoft resources to define build standards and document operational processes.
- Worked with Operations teams to resolve stability problems, improve service uptime, and integrate best practices into future requirements.
- Collaborated with Capacity and Operations teams to plan and execute the migration of virtual machines in support of shared goal to reduce demand for VMware licensing.
- Developed culture of collaboration with Operations group to focus work on our shared goals.

2010-12 -2012-04

Sr Systems Engineer

Teletech Holdings, Englewood, CO

 Standardized VMware hypervisor builds and rebuilt environment to a consistent state reducing the number of issues.

2006-07 -2010-12

Microsoft Systems Engineer II

Catholic Health Initiatives, Englewood, CO

- Implemented VMware infrastructure for business services and products.
- Reduced datacenter costs for space and cooling with physical server consolidation.

Education

Master of Science: Computer Information

Systems

Regis University - Denver, CO

Non-Degree Certificate: Full Stack Web Development

University of Denver - Denver, CO

Certifications

The Open Group Architecture Framework (TOGAF)9
ITIL Foundation

ITIL Intermediate Certificate in IT Service Operation Lean IT Foundation

Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure (MCSE: Cloud)